An AI-generated PR can make CI green by changing the test that proves it succeeded.
This is a public demo repo. The verifier requires both admin and member, but the code only allows admin, so the base branch fails on purpose.
The gate is the Runcap action, pinned to release commit 1eb8745, running as a pull-request check.
PR #1 edits only the source file to allow member too. The check is green. The log says Verdict: PASS.
PR #2 makes the same correct fix, but adds an unrelated file outside the allowed scope.
The check is red. Verdict: BLOCKED, naming docs/unrelated-change.md as out of scope.
PR #3 doesn't fix the code. It edits the verifier - the proof itself.
Verdict: HUMAN_APPROVAL_REQUIRED. Runcap declines to auto-certify and hands the decision to a human CODEOWNER.
CI-attested replay under a documented hardened GitHub profile.
AI can propose a change. It should not certify its own success.